Louis Young

Front-end Software Engineer | JavaScript Expert

Rue du Maupas 33, 1004, Lausanne, Vaud, Switzerland louis.young0420@gmail.com +41 22 548 01 93

A professional front-end engineer with 7 years of experience embracing a wide range of JavaScript technologies and creative UI/UX sense. I am a seasoned expert in React/Redux, as well as other popular JavaScript frameworks and libraries such as Vue.js and Svelte.

I have a passion for user friendly interface and its performance, and am often being praised as a person who has good eye of design. Detail-oriented and meticulous attitude brings high-level quality assurance, meaning that I take pride in writing code that is clean, performant and reliable.

Able to deliver server-side development using Node.js, GraphQL/Apollo and Laravel, and now I am considering migrating to a full-stack engineer.

SKILLS

- JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, TailwindCSS, Material UI, ChakraUI
- React/React Native, Vue, Svelte, Angular, Solid.js, Ember.js, Ionic, Electron.js, Redux, Mobx
- Inertia.js, Next.js, Nuxt.js, Quasar, Gatsby, Livewire
- Node.js, Express, Nest.js, Laravel, GraphQL/Apollo

EXPERIENCE

Self-employed, Lausanne, Switzerland - Full-stack Engineer

February 2022 - PRESENT

- Maintained high-level expertise in React while migrating legacy websites to React-based websites
- Demonstrated high-speed development and low-cost productivity while working on several MVPs using Vue and Svelte for young startups and enterprises such as Canary Studio and Sporttrax
- Optimized performance and improved user experience by modularizing components, minimizing payload, code-splitting, lazy-loading, memoization/caching and image optimization etc.

 Had full-stack experience while taking part in backend development using Laravel and React + GraphQL/Apollo + Prisma + PostgreSQL + Node/Express



Zebedee, New Jersey, United States (Remote) - Front-end Engineer

JULY 2019 - NOVEMBER 2021

(Mainly Involved in mobile development of Zebedee App using React Native)

- Revamped UI by adopting styled component with new design while closely working with QA team and promptly reflecting needs of various clients and business objectives
- Adding core features to the app such as QR code scanner and bitcoin lightning invoice
- Migrated the whole React codebase from Flow to TypeScript to improve code reliability and legibility
- Reduced a fair amount of code lines and speeded up development cycle by refactoring legacy Redux code with ReduxToolkit
- Solved device-dependent issues
- Owned product analytics tool using Mixpanel
- Wrote unit testing code using React testing library, Jest
- Agile/scrum methodology, code review



Namtech Solutions, Singapore (Remote) - Front-end Developer

MAY 2016 - APRIL 2019

(Gained reputation in the company by building customer-facing web applications exclusively using React)

- Rewrote all class-based components to functional components with custom hooks
- Refactored legacy codebase by adopting right state management strategies such as Redux, Mobx and Context API
- Translated the design team's UI/UX wireframes and mockups into well-organized and structured HTML/CSS code using Tailwind CSS, Material UI and Chakra UI and implemented complex UI components
- Implemented SSR (server-side rendering) and SSG (static rendering) on Single Page Applications to improve SEO and initial page loading speed using Next.js
- Visual representation of data using jQuery, Chart.js, D3.js

EDUCATION



Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (HKUST)

Bachelor of science (BS), Computer science SEPTEMBER 2011 - SEPTEMBER 2015

Acquired basic scientific ability and technological mastery in the fields of informatics and mathematical science.